JONATHAN VARGAS

San Antonio, TX (210) 550 - 6119 11jonathanvargas11@gmail.com

Analyst, Developer, Penetration Tester.

I am a Senior undergraduate at the University of Texas at San Antonio majoring in Cyber Security and Information Systems. I am enthusiastic about hardening operating systems and network security and strive to lead the next generation of cyber security professionals. My goal is to find opportunities to apply my diligently-learned principles of security with a team that encourages innovation and leadership.

I have authored various penetration testing methodology articles on my website, organized a cyber security CTF competition for two ethical hacking online communities, and acquired industry IT experience during my undergraduate studies through two internships and one contract opportunity. Through extracurricular activities, I have consulted with leaders in my field on security practices and headed an on-campus organization with weekly lessons.



Offensive Security Certified Professional

01/2021

The OSCP exam is a 24-hour practical ethical hacking test offered by Offensive Security. By becoming an Offensive Security Certified Professional, I have demonstrated the ability to use persistence, creativity, and perceptiveness to identify vulnerabilities in remote Windows and Linux servers while executing organized attacks under tight time constraints.

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/bbe5bdbb-3a9d-4cea-972c-6aee0974e8d6/public url

CompTIA Security+

08/2020

By obtaining this certification, I have demonstrated the skills necessary to perform core security functions required of any cybersecurity role. I understand how to identify and address potential threats, attacks and vulnerabilities and I have established techniques in risk management, risk mitigation, threat management and intrusion detection.

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/75da2bbe-0014-4f4d-9f9d-281c19150a0f/public url



WORK EXPERIENCE

Cyber Security CTF Organizer

08/2020 to 08/2020

Self

San Antonio, TX

- Executed an open capture-the-flag competition for members of the Try Hack Me and Hack The Box ethical
 hacking communities. Two teams of five members were tasked with exploiting a remote server, gaining access,
 then establishing tighter security controls in order for the opposing team to fail at breaching entry.
- Assembled a collection of three exploitable machines containing vulnerabilities in line with the Open Web Application Security Project's (OWASP) top ten security risks.
- Researched real-world security compromising incidents and integrated recent exploits into the competition's vulnerable machines.

SQL Developer

02/2020 to 08/2020

Ward North American

San Antonio, TX

- Optimize MS SQL reporting scripts for lower data retrieval latency.
- · Debug live SQL reports for misreported values.
- Collaborate with various department managers to build new tables and reports that fit the department's requirements.
- Write over 5,000 lines of code monthly to adjust for the company's changing data management practices.

President

05/2019 to 05/2020

UTSA Swing Dance Society

San Antonio, TX

- Headed a student-led organization to preserve the social dance and culture of the swing jazz era
- · Orchestrated weekly dance instruction
- · Cultivated a Board of Executives
- Partnered with community and intercollegiate organizations

IT Intern

03/2019 to 02/2020

Ward North American

San Antonio, TX

- Spearheaded the development of aggregation software to understand sales trends
- · Developed two complex SQL and JDBC algorithms to fully automate corporate budget analysis
- Inspired the prototyping of Ward University: a learning management system for small corporations.
- Collaborated closely with cloud service provider to ensure network reliability.
- Offered expert IT troubleshooting and consultation for software and hardware solutions.
- Gained experience using Wireshark to monitor network activity and identify network issues.

• Developed automated emails to be sent out to customers and agents.

Cyber Security Intern

07/2017 to 03/2018

Alamo City Engineering Services

San Antonio, TX

- Acquired industry hands-on open source intelligence experience through utilizing deep web data crawling APIs.
- Collaborated with a team to delegate tasks and develop strategies to implement information system automation software.

 EDUCATION	

University of Texas at San Antonio

Bachelor's Cyber Security, Information Systems San Antonio, TX 08/2017 to 05/2021



----- SKILLS ------

- Information Assurance
- Penetration Testing
- System Administration
- Web Application Security
- Network Security
- Help Desk

- Active Directory
- Threat Remidiation
- Vulnerability Assessment
GROUPS
UTSA Computer Security Association
 Attended weekly discussions on current security trends, automation tools, and information security principles. Visited online workshops for further developing cyber security skills such as risk mitigation, executing security assessments for real world companies, and security hardening tools. Consulted with higher-experienced members of my field to explore industry standards and practices.
UTSA Swing Dance Society
 Headed a student-led organization to preserve the social dance and culture of the swing jazz era Orchestrated weekly dance instruction Cultivated a Board of Executives Partnered with community organizations.

 $https://vargasportfolio.github.io/ \sim Cyber\ Security\ Portfolio\ and\ Penetration\ Test\ Writeups$